# Nicholas Kiermaier



nickkiermaier@gmail.com



https://0foo.dev

# Summary

Experienced Sytems Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Strong engineering professional with a Master's degree(all but thesis) and knowledge of all levels of the stack: infrastructure, data layer, middleware, and front end.

# **Experience**



# in Site Reliability Engineer

LinkedIn

Mar 2022 - Mar 2023 (1 year 1 month)

Part of team managing build process of servers at scale building from bare metal to fully configured OS all controlled by in house python/bash applications configuring/controlling host via: IPMI, Kickstart, and numerous custom daemons interacting with package management and other configuration solutions

Part of team to manage enterprise scale internal yum infrastructure

### Software Engineer III

Tulane National Primate Research Center

Nov 2019 - Mar 2022 (2 years 5 months)

Part of a team to transition the centerwide legacy LIMS to a more modern system.

The TNPRC LIMS manages the entire Primate Center and captures tens of thousands of records per month and millions of dollars in research funding.

Worked with Java, Javascript, Server Management, MSSQL databases.

# **Cloud Engineer**

**DXC Technology** 

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Member of a team developing a managed services application for clients that automates infrastructure, security, backups, and monitoring.

AWS offerings: Config, Cloudwatch, Cloudformation, Lambda, CodeBuild, EC2, SSM, Secrets Manager,

Workspaces, S3, EFS, IAM, Guard Duty, VPC

Other tools: Docker, Troposphere, Python, Linux, Git

Agile: Jira, Scrum, Standups, Retro



### Software Engineer/Systems Engineer

Nov 2016 - Jul 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Develop, troubleshoot, and maintain PHP and Javascript applications for the marketing industry.

Solve emergent engineering problems to leverage millions of records of data to provide business value in the marketing industry

Implement dashboard solutions to provide visualization and statistical analysis of data

Languages: Php 7+, Python, Javascript

Cloud: AWS-SQS, Lambda, ECS, EC2, EFS, VPC, S3, Route 53, ELB, Athena

Containerization: Docker, ECS

Frameworks: Laravel, Symfony, RiotJs

Datastores: RDS, MySql, Postgres, Redshift, EFS, S3

OS: Linux

Other Tools: Artilleryjs, Serverless, Git, Nightmarejs, Casperjs, Private Packagist, Sentry, Uptrends

IDE: Phpstorm, Sublime, Atom

Agile: Jira, Trello, Scrum, Standups, Retrospectives

### Web Developer

Force Multiplier Solutions

Mar 2015 - Nov 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Develop, troubleshoot, and maintain Rails, Python, and PHP applications for the transportation industry.

Implement data abstraction layers/parsers for software interfaces between different organizations.

Implement on time arrival solutions for transit organizations using real time GPS.

Implement Rspec tests and Factory girl factories for Rails applications.

Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, Rspec, Factory Girl, Linux, GTFS, KML, GPS

### **Graduate Assistant**

University of New Orleans

Aug 2012 - Feb 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Developed and maintained internal/external websites using HTML\CSS\JavaScript, Java, JSP, Wordpress.

Participated in release management of proprietary field research software into thin client devices.

Assisted laboratory staff with computer lab management and provided technical support help

Assisted math and computer science faculty and staff with technology support related issues.

### 🗑 Systems Engineer II

**Tulane University** 

Feb 2011 - Aug 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Imaging, backup, configuration of Microsoft and Linux servers

Managed software configurations, builds, and deployments in both Windows and Mac OS X environments.

Provided technical support to researchers, doctors, and scientists with software related issues.

Technologies used included: Windows Server, Mac Os X, Linux.

### **Education**



### Louisiana State University

Bachelor's degree, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2003 - 2007



### **University of New Orleans**

Master's degree, Computer Science 2012 - 2016

# **Licenses & Certifications**

CCENT - Cisco

Issued Jan 2015 - Expires Jan 2018

Amazon Web Services Developer - Associate - Amazon

Issued Nov 2019 - Expires Nov 2022 3P97PVVCME11Q05D

(CKAD) Certified Kubernetes Application Developer - The Linux Foundation

Issued Nov 2020 - Expires Nov 2023 LF-bsfewf3gvw

### **Skills**

Bash • Python • Git • SQL • Linux • JavaScript • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Networking • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Kubernetes